<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ANDREFFS</title>
    <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ANDREFFS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andreffs18.github.io/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/debug-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 06:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/debug-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>While building this website I needed to understand a bit more about the internals and its variables. Eventhough Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation about debugging is pretty &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo;, there are a lot of attributes that are really hard to figure out, specially if you can&amp;rsquo;t see them on the documentation.
So I started to look online for something to help me out debugging Hugo templates and the usual 3 options were:
 🖨 printing the dot on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s templates 📝 console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just keep on &#34;Save for later&#34;</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/just-keep-on-save-for-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/just-keep-on-save-for-later/</guid>
      <description>Since this #remotelife began, sadly not for the best reasons, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to finally clean my backlog of, guess what, TV Shows, Games, Podcasts, Books&amp;hellip; Well, everything that a person is suppose to do!
Very happy was I until I remembered that, maybe I should start looking into the &amp;ldquo;To Read&amp;rdquo; bookmarks, &amp;ldquo;Saved&amp;rdquo; on Reddit and, the holy grail, &amp;ldquo;Read Later&amp;rdquo; of Feedly.
While the &amp;ldquo;Saved&amp;rdquo; section on Reddit was mostly threads from /r/cscarrearquestions (and some memes from /r/wsb 😂) the other two places were actual interesting articles that I have planned on reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/docker-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 17:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/docker-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>More often than not, I end up going online to look up on how to use docker as the middle man on interacting with Postgres.
 Usually for me its Postgres, but this &amp;ldquo;recipe&amp;rdquo; can be applied to any piece of software that has more than one version which you don&amp;rsquo;t have installed on your laptop.
 Because of this whole back and forth I compiled a small list of &amp;ldquo;how-tos&amp;rdquo; to help me remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Canary Deploy with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/learning-how-to-canary-deploy-with-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/learning-how-to-canary-deploy-with-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Its true, that if the time from developing a feature to deploying it to your customers only takes minutes to hours instead of days to months, that you probably have a pretty amazing development workflow.
Im also willing to bet that a key feature of that workflow is an impeccable CI/CD pipeline, that not only allows your development team to automate a lot of time consuming and manual tasks (like building, testing, deploying, etc) but also, shortens the feedback cycle between developing-&amp;gt;testing and testing-&amp;gt;production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH ForwardAgent Gotchas</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/ssh-forwardagent-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/ssh-forwardagent-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>So, you’re trying to create an SSH Tunnel to your remote machine to make some gitlab/github clones.
That’s all fine and well until you don’t want to post your password on to the terminal.
First, look at you ~/.ssh/config file and add the “ForwardAgent yes” to that machines ip.
1 2 3  Host 35.241.133.24 IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_rsa ForwardAgent yes   That says to use your local private key as identification when accessing gitlab on your remote’s machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgres Is Now Running</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/postgres-is-now-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 10:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/postgres-is-now-running/</guid>
      <description>My macbook has OSX Mavericks installed and sometimes it crashes for no reason, breaking my local postgres server. After restarting and running again &amp;quot;$ brew services postgres&amp;quot;, Postgres becomes yellow and I end up spending sometime looking confused and frustrated.
Looking at the logs you can get a sense of whats happening:
1 2  $ tail -f /usr/local/var/postgres/server.log FATAL: lock file &amp;#34;postmaster.pid&amp;#34; already exists   Simply removing the lock file that Postgres generates solves this issue:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💰 Personal Finance</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/personal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/personal-finance/</guid>
      <description>Well, after reading a couple of books on the topic, they all talk about the same thing: you should diversify your portfolio.
Code could not finish, this are some reasons why this happen. - Plot name not defined. The first parameter of the shortcode is the name. - There is a syntax error. check browser console.   function draw(){ test = document.getElementById(&#34;piechart&#34;); if (test == null){ console.log(&#34;The plot name is not defined&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO Tips</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/seo-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/seo-tips/</guid>
      <description>My key takeaways from making this website &amp;ldquo;SEO friendly&amp;rdquo;:
 Use link &amp;ldquo;tree structure&amp;rdquo; from homepage. This way, bots and crawlers can find every page on the website Good titles, under 65 characters Meta tags with good keywords under 100 characters Use canonical urls on every page  1 2 3  &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;canonical&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/seo-tips/&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- instead of --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;canonical&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;/blog/seo-tips&amp;#34;&amp;gt;   Add &amp;ldquo;alt&amp;rdquo; tag to images  1  &amp;lt;img alt=&amp;#34;About me picture&amp;#34; src=&amp;#34;/images/about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Paid For Pooping</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/get-paid-for-pooping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 13:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/get-paid-for-pooping/</guid>
      <description>Yes I know it sounds dumb but, if during your working hours you go to the toilet, technically, you are getting paid for it. 💩
Use case Alright, lets say you you earn $10 an hour and during those 8 hours of daily work, you go twice to the bathroom, for around 10 minutes each time.
Then a simple multiplication shows that your &amp;ldquo;poop time&amp;rdquo; is worth around $3.34 per day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 00:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello 😃
So this is the mandatory &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; blog post.
The intent of this blog is just to keep track of my achievements, projects and also:
 Technical how-to/tutorials Bugs or gotchas that might be useful in the future Setup &amp;amp; configuration Stuff that I keep forgetting and keep googling.  👋</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some of my side projects:    Flask Template Bootstrap Flask project to use in Hackathons.
 python       Santosbot Motivational Slack bot that mimic cliché sentences from Portuguese guru, Gustavo Santos.
 python3 async heroku vuejs      andreffs.com This website, build with Hugo.
 hugo go jupyter notebooks static hosting      Sheetsu Python SDK I had the luck of being feature for building Sheetsu&amp;#39;s Python SDK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/about/</guid>
      <description>👋 My name is André Silva and I&amp;rsquo;m a 28 y/old Portuguese Software Engineer from Lisbon that likes to code.
# A bit about me I wasn&amp;rsquo;t always focused on the development world.
During high school I got the change to internship on a consulting firm in my hometown, mainly working with setting up data centers, and configuring network systems.
After high school I went to college to take a Computer Science Bachelor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreffs18.github.io/website/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>